Finding Aid for Hobart Taylor, Jr. Papers 1961-1981
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Topical File
  - Detroit Economic Club (Box 17)
  - Detroit Edison Company (Box 17)
  - Detroit Museum of Art (Box 17)
  - Dillard University (Box 17)
  - District of Columbia Commission on the Arts (Box 17)
  - District of Columbia Mental Health Association (Box 17)
  - Dixon, Sgt. Miller A (Box 17)
  - Dominican Republic (Box 17)
  - Dukes, Ofield (Box 17)
  - Fairchild Industries, Inc (Box 17)
  - Federal Bar Association (Box 17)
  - Federal Conference Center (Box 17)
  - 33 Fifth Avenue Company (Box 17)
  - First City Bancorporation of Texas (Box 17)
  - First Eastern Company, Ltd (Box 17)
  - Golden State Mutual Life Insurance Company (Box 17)
  - Great Atlantic & Pacific Tea Company
    - General Correspondence 1973 (Box 17)
    - Memoranda re: Board Meetings (Box 17)
    - Legal Documents (Box 17)
  - Great Plains Partnership (Box 17)
  - Hampton Institute (Box 17)
  - Harbor Isle Spa (Box 17)
  - Harthe, Senator Vance (Box 17)
  - Heroes, Inc (Box 17)
  - Holland, Ambassador Jerome (Box 17)
  - Hotel St. Regis (Box 17)
  - Howard University (Box 17)
  - Human Relations Institute (Box 17)
  - Humphrey, Hubert H (Box 17)
  - Indiana National Bank (Box 17)
  - Inaugural Committee 1965
    - General Information (Box 17)
    - Correspondence (Box 17)
    - Invitation Lists (Box 17)
  - Inter-American Bar Association (Box 17)
  - International Club (Box 17)
  - Ivory Coast (Box 17)
  - Janeway, Eliot Correspondence 1961-1973, 4 folders (Box 17)
  - Johnson, Lyndon Baines
    - Correspondence and Memoranda 1962-1973, 5 folders (Box 18)
    - Letters for the President's Signature (Box 18)
    - Newspaper Clippings re. Death of Lyndon Johnson (Box 18)
  - Johnson, Mrs. Lyndon B. (Lady Bird) (Box 18)
  - Joint Center For Political Studies (Box 18)
  - Jones, Howard L (Box 18)
  - Laird, Melvin (Box 18)
  - Lansburgh, Morris (Box 18)
  - Lawyers' Study Group (Box 18)
  - Lerner Oil Co., Inc (Box 18)
  - Levine, Lawrence Correspondence 1969-1975, 3 folders (Box 18)
  - Lewis & Peat Limited (Box 18)
  - Ling-Temco-Vought, Inc. Correspondence 1967-1970, 3 folders (Box 18)
  - Loomis Institute (Box 18)
  - Lyford Cay Club (Box 18)
  - Lynch, Curtis Lee (Box 18)
  - Lynn, The Honorable James T (Box 18)
  - Maryland Farms (Box 18)
  - McClellan Committee (Box 18)
  - Medical Mission Sisters Correspondence 1967-1975, 3 folders (Box 18)
  - Misuraca, Henry A (Box 18)
  - Mobil Oil Corporation (Box 18)
  - Motown Correspondence 1969-1975, 4 folders (Box 18)
  - Museum of African Art (Box 18)
  - National Alliance of Businessmen (Box 18)
  - National Capital Democratic Club (Box 18)
  - National Conference of Commissioners on Uniform State Laws (Box 18)
  - National Council of Churches (Box 18)
  - National Council on Crime and Delinquency (Box 18)
  - National Fund for Minority Engineering Students (Box 18)
  - National Industrial Conference Board (Box 18)
  - National Labor Relations Board (Box 18)
  - National Merit Scholarship Corporation Correspondence 1967-1969, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - National Merit Scholarship Corporation Correspondence 1970-1973, 4 folders (Box 19)
  - National Minority Purchasing Council (Box 19)
  - National Park Foundation (Box 19)
  - National Symphony Orchestra Association (Box 19)
  - National Teacher Association Project Counsel (Box 19)
  - National Urban League Award (Box 19)
  - Newcomer Society in North America (Box 19)
  - New Executive Order 1965 (Box 19)
  - New Zealand Trip 1974 (Box 19)
  - New Zealand/United States Arts Association (Box 19)
  - On the Job Training Ideas and Information, Inc (Box 19)
  - Oriental Ceramic Society (Box 19)
  - Overseas Development Corporation (Box 19)
  - Owens-Illinois Corporation Correspondence 1970-1972, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Palme, Claes (Box 19)
  - Pisces (Box 19)
  - Poage Congressional Library (Box 19)
  - Political Observations (Box 19)
  - Prairie View A & M University (Box 19)
  - President's Commission on Executive Exchange (Box 19)
  - President's Commission on White House Fellows (Box 19)
  - Proctor & Gamble Company
    - Correspondence 1970-1973, 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Buckeye Cellulose Corporation (Box 19)
    - Sex Discrimination Charge (Box 19)
  - Prudential Year End Drilling Fund 1969 (Box 19)
  - Puerto Rican Civil Rights League, Inc (Box 19)
  - Puerto Rico (Box 19)
  - Pullman Incorporated
    - General Correspondence 1969-1970, 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Bessemer Plant, 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Equal Employment Opportunity Committee (Box 19)
    - Swindell-Dressler Company
      - General Correspondence 1971-1972, 2 folders (Box 19)
      - Clippings and Releases (Box 19)
      - Russian Trade Delegation and Itinerary (Box 19)
  - Pullman v. John A. Volpe et. al., 3 folders (Box 20)
  - Reality Equities Corp. General Correspondence 1969-1975, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Reedy, George (Box 20)
  - Roumell Catering Company (Box 20)
  - Saturday Morning Group (Box 20)
  - Shaw University (Box 20)
  - Smith-Bisschop and Co (Box 20)
  - Smithsonian Institution (Box 20)
  - Soil & Health Foundation (Box 20)
  - South African Trip 1973 (Box 20)
  - Spiner, Pritchard & Thompson (Box 20)
  - Standard Oil of Ohio (Box 20)
  - Supreme Court Historical Society (Box 20)
  - Swainson, Governor John B (Box 20)
  - Taylor, Patrick, Bailer, Wexler, & Brookins (Box 20)
  - Taylor, Mrs. Willie Day (Box 20)
  - Technical Tape Corporation (Box 20)
  - Texas Breakfast Club (Box 20)
  - Texas Politics 1961-1963 (Box 20)
  - Textron, Inc (Box 20)
  - Tuckahoe Road Company (Box 20)
  - Tuesday Publications, Inc (Box 20)
  - United Givers Fund of the National Capital Area (Box 20)
  - United Negro College Fund Campaign 1965 (Box 20)
  - United States Supreme Court Historical Society (Box 20)
  - University Club (New York City) (Box 20)
  - University of Michigan
    - General Correspondence 1975-1978 (Box 20)
    - Committee of Visitors Correspondence 1966-1970, 3 folders (Box 20)
    - Development Council Correspondence 1969-1977, 4 folders (Box 20)
    - Law School Correspondence 1971-1977, 3 folders (Box 20)
    - Michigan Historical Collections
      - General (Box 20)
      - Sculpture dedication 1975 (Box 20)
    - National Institute of Occupational Safety and Health (Box 20)
    - Presidents Club Correspondence 1971-1977, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Urban League (Milwaukee, Wisconsin) (Box 20)
  - Urban National Corporation Correspondence 1970-1978, 3 folders (Box 20)
  - Volunteer leadership Committee on Genetics (Box 20)
  - Volunteers for International Technical Assistance, Inc (Box 20)
  - Washington Admirals Club (Box 21)
  - Washington Cathedral (Box 21)
  - Washington Community Broadcasting (Box 21)
  - Washington National Symphony (Box 21)
  - Washington Performing Arts Society (Box 21)
  - Wellington Management Company (Box 21)
  - Westinghouse Electric Corporation (Box 21)
  - White House Staff Correspondence and Memoranda 1963-1971, 9 folders (Box 21)
  - Willard Alexander, Inc (Box 21)
  - Wilson Center Correspondence 1978-1981, 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Wolftrap Foundation For The Performing Arts
    - Correspondence 1969-1981, 9 folders (Box 21)
    - By-laws, agreement, etc (Box 21)
    - Executive Committee minutes (Box 21)
    - Finance Committee (Box 21)
    - Government Liaison Committee (Box 21)
    - Nominating Committee (Box 21)
    - Search Committee (Box 21)
  - Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars (Box 21)
  - Yntema, Hessel (Box 21)
  - Zieger Osteopathic Hospital, Inc
    - General correspondence 1961-1968 (Box 21)
    - Board of Directors minutes 1961-1968, 8 folders (Box 21)
    - Yearly reports 1961-1963 (Box 21)
    - Miscellaneous reports and publications (Box 21)
- Awards and citations
  Throughout his life, Hobart Taylor, Jr. received many honors which have been placed in the Awards and Citations series.
  - Various citations (Box 22)
    (also in oversize box 25)
- Photographs
  Photographs are divided into two subseries, topical and chronological, although there is some duplication of topics between the two subseries. The photos are made up almost exclusively of photos of Taylor at meetings, in groups of people, and greeting and conversing with others. Photos of Taylor with John F. Kennedy, Lyndon B. Johnson, and Hubert H. Humphrey are found throughout, especially in the Plans for Progress folders. One photo of Taylor as a University of Michigan student is found in the Miscellaneous folder.
  - Topical file
    (also in oversize box 24-25)
    - Dinners (Box 23)
    - Family (Box 23)
    - Friends and colleagues (Box 23)
    - Groups
      - Formal (Box 23)
      - Identified (Box 23)
      - Unidentified (Box 23)
    - Hunt, Richard
      - Bentley Library courtyard sculpture
        - Drawings, installation, etc (Box 23)
        - Dedication September 14, 1975 (Box 23)
      - Other sculptures (Box 23)
    - Johnson, Lyndon B (Box 23)
    - Kennedy, John F (Box 23)
    - NASA (Box 23)
    - Plans for Progress
      - General, 2 folders (Box 23)
      - Los Angeles, Calif (Box 23)
      - Cruises (Box 23)
      - Signing November 30, 1961, June 22, 1962 (Box 23)
      - Committee Meeting May 29, 1963 (Box 23)
      - Conference at White House December 12, 1963 (Box 23)
      - Annual Meeting 1964 (Box 23)
      - College Placement Council, Washington, D.C. 1964 (Box 23)
      - Third National Conference January 1965 (Box 23)
      - Vice President's Task Force on Youth Motivation, Decatur House April 1965 (Box 23)
      - San Francisco Regional Conference June 10, 1965 (Box 23)
      - Press preview for national advertising September 30, 1965 (Box 23)
      - Fourth National Conference January 24-25, 1966 (Box 23)
      - Sixth National Conference January 22-23, 1968 (Box 23)
    - Portraits (Box 23)
  - Chronological file
    - 1961 (Box 23)
    - 1962
      - General (Box 23)
      - Community leaders confab (Box 23)
      - Meeting of President's Committee on Equal Employment Opportunities, February 15 (Box 23)
      - Indian Treaty Room, Executive Office Building, August 22 (Box 23)
    - 1963 (Box 23)
    - 1964
      - General (Box 23)
      - Eastern Region confab, June 11 (Box 23)
    - 1965
      - General (Box 23)
      - Presentation of National Urban League Achievement Award to Hobart Taylor, July (Box 23)
    - 1966 (Box 23)
    - 1967 (Box 23)
    - 1968 (Box 23)
    - 1969 (Box 23)
    - 1970 (Box 23)
    - 1971 (Box 23)
    - 1972 (Box 23)
    - 1973 (Box 23)
    - 1974
      - General (Box 23)
      - Visit of board of directors of SOHIO to Prudhoe Bay, Alaska (Box 23)
    - 1975 (Box 23)
    - 1976 (Box 23)
    - 1977
      - General (Box 23)
      - Visit of board of directors of SOHIO to Prudhoe Bay, Alaska, July 24-28 (Box 23)
    - 1978 (Box 23)
    - 1979 (Box 23)
    - 1980 (Box 23)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Unidentified, etc (Box 23)
    - Outsize prints (many autographed by public figures) (Box 24)
- Awards and Official Documents
  - Awards, diplomas, presidential appointments, etc., 16 items (Box 25)